Omari Sharpe

Queens, NY | (718) 541-9276

<u>osharpe001@gmail.com</u> | <u>osharpesportfolio.vercel.app</u> | <u>linkedin.com/in/omarisharpe</u> | <u>https://github.com/OSharpe001</u>

SUMMARY:

Detail-oriented web developer with strong analytical skills. Practical experience after college-level training with various programming languages. Resourceful with a solid grasp of technical skills and coding techniques. An adaptive frame of mind and extremely organized. Strong collaboration skills, diligent work ethics, and critical thinking capabilities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

JAVASCRIPT | HTML5 & CSS3 | PYTHON3 | RESTFUL API | NODE.JS | SPRING BOOT WITH JAVA | PHP | REACT | EXPRESS | DJANGO | JSON | SQL & NOSQL | GIT & GITHUB

EDUCATION:

- Per Scholas | Software Engineering Bootcamp | New York, NY Anticipated Graduation: September 2023
- Vaughn College of Aeronautics and Technology | Queens, NY Bachelor of Science in Aviation Maintenance Honors: 3.54 GPA

CERTIFICATIONS:

Meta Front-End Developer Coursera	3/11/2023
Web Applications for Everybody Coursera	6/27/2022
PostgreSQL for Everybody Coursera	5/10/2022
Python 3 Programming Coursera	4/29/2022
AWS Fundamentals Coursera	3/11/2022
Django for Everybody Coursera	2/28/2022
Python for Everybody Coursera	11/18/2021
JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Free Code Camp	10/31/2022
Responsive Web Design Free Code Camp	9/29/2022

EMPLOYMENT:

Union Electrician | J & G Electric | New York City, NY

07/2021 - 08/2021

- Wired fire alarm systems and devices, motors, and motor control apparatus for safety and operations
- Plotted and install raceway conduits, lighting fixtures, and other electrical devices
- Calculated total current load and paths of circuits to ensure proper operation of devices and safety
- Troubleshoot electrical issues to resolve hazardous and unsightly situations

Union Electrician | Thorn Electric | New York City, NY

10/2018 - 01/2021

- Wired fire alarm systems and devices, motors, and motor control apparatus for safety and operations
- Plotted and install raceway conduits, lighting fixtures, and other electrical devices
- Calculated total current load and paths of circuits to ensure proper operation of devices and safety
- Troubleshoot electrical issues to resolve hazardous and unsightly situations

Union Electrician | B & G Electric | New York City, NY

02/2018 - 10/2018

- Wired fire alarm systems and devices, motors, and motor control apparatus for safety and operations
- Plotted and install raceway conduits, lighting fixtures, and other electrical devices
- Calculated total current load and paths of circuits to ensure proper operation of devices and safety

Troubleshoot electrical issues to resolve hazardous and unsightly situations

Union Electrician and Foreman | H & L Electric | New York City, NY

1/2013 - 11/2017

- Consulted with clients regarding current and future project parameters
- Executed timeline management to complete projects over 10% faster than the designated schedule
- Ensured productivity of managed coworkers and quality of their work to continue high integrity of the finished product and saved over 10% of the budget by reducing waste of materials and time
- Fulfilled Electrician Duties (as stated in other companies above)

PROJECTS:

- Pokemon Memory Match Game: An "offline-multiplayer", child friendly card matching game that's fun for all ages! Optimized for both desktop and mobile screen sizes. Created utilizing JavaScript, HTML, CSS and a RESTful API | https://osharpe001.github.io/
- Our Tip Calculator: A simple and intuitive tip calculator. Great for saving embarrassment when dining out with friends! Optimized for both desktop and mobile screen sizes. Created utilizing JavaScript, HTML and CSS | https://ourtipcalculator.netlify.app/
- Letter To Success: An "offline-multiplayer" parody of the hit game show Wheel Of Fortune. Optimized for both desktop and mobile screen sizes. Created utilizing React, JavaScript, HTML and CSS https://lettertosuccess.netlify.app/
- Little Lemon Bistro: Restaurant webpage complete with sign-up/sign-in and delivery functionality. Optimized for both desktop and mobile screen sizes. Created utilizing React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS https://littlelemonbistro.vercel.app/
 1/2023 2/2023